ほんとは あのこより
ぼくのほうが はやい
She thought that she could win,
but there was no way.
Next year,
I’ll be the fastest kid in the entire school!
らいねんは ぼくが
がっこうで 1ばんになる
ぼくが きみの がっこうに
いないからね
That’s ‘cause I’m not in your school.
なに いってんの！
Oh, please!
Remember last time
こないだ かいしゅう みんなの
まえで ぼくが かっただろ
when I beat you in front
of the whole congregation?
Caleb, do you remember this story?
カレブ この おはなし
おぼえてる？
Oh, yeah,
うん
バベルのとう
that’s the Tower of Babel.
That’s right!
そのとおり！
Why were these people
trying to build this tower?
どうして このひとたちは
とうを たてようとしたの？
So they could live there?
それは……
すむため？
Actually,
ほんとは じぶんたちが
すごいってことを
it was because they thought
they were awesome
みせびらかしたかったんだ
and wanted to show off.
でも エホバは
それを どうおもった？
But what did Jehovah think of that?
Oh, he didn’t like it.
うーん
いやだった
That’s right.
そう
He even confused their languages
それで ことばを こんらんさせて
じまんできなくしたんだ
so they would stop bragging.
でも がっこうじゃ
みんな じまんしてるよ
But at school everyone brags!
I know.
そうだね
じまんするひとが おおいね
Lots of people brag.
I have bragged too.
パパも じまんしたことがある
But that’s wrong.
でも それは まちがってる
じまんすることや みせびらかすことは
When we brag or show off,
it’s like we are building
じぶんのために バベルのとうを
たてるようなものなんだ
a tower for ourselves,
just like the Tower of Babel.
ぼくが ほんきになれば
せかいきろくだって らくしょうだ！
If I wanted to,
I could set a new world record
—no problem!
バスケットボールだったら
ぼくのほうが ぜったい うまい
If you say so.
But I’m better at basketball than you.
ぼくが ギターの てんさいだって
みんなが いってる
I was just messing around,
but they say I’m a natural.
The higher up we try to put ourselves,
うえに いけば いくほど
どんどん あぶなくなるんだよ
the more dangerous it gets.
Do you know why?
なぜだか わかる？
Because we’ll eventually fall?
いつかは おちちゃうから？
わっ わっ
Whoa, whoa.
わぁー
Whoa!
ふっ
Ooph!
そう
Yes!
Also, 1 Peter 5:5
それに ペテロだいいち
5しょう 5せつで
みんなが えらそうにしないようにと
means that Jehovah
doesn’t want us acting like
エホバは
ねがっておられることが わかる
we are better than everyone else.
Humble people don’t need to brag,
エホバは けんそんな ひとを
しあわせな きもちに してくださるから
because Jehovah will make them
だれも じまんしなくて いいんだよ
feel good about themselves
on the inside.